CHRISTOPHER LACHANCE

https://ctlachance.com | https://github.com/CTLaChance | christopher.t.lachance@gmail.com | (409) 543 - 8490

Personal Summary

Artist and Software Engineer with a passion for music, minimalism, and modern design. Experienced in a wide array of creative disciplines, capable of rapidly acquiring new skills and technologies, and always ready for the next challenge. Excited to begin building a lifelong career in the web development ecosystem.

Technology Experience

Programming Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript ES6+, C#, Java, Lua, C++

Style/Markup Languages: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, XML, Markdown

Miscellaneous: NodeJS, Svelte, React, Git, SVN, Linux, CI/CD (Google

Cloud), Bash, Unity 3D, Photoshop, Virtual Reality

Professional Experience

AGS, LLC January 2018 - Present

Software Engineer

- Redesigned critical game logic to meet the demands of complex math models
- Worked collaboratively with artists, musicians, and game designers to implement their design vision without compromise
- Handled various DevOps challenges that arose from working in a small team environment
- · Lead Engineer for the following 9 games:

Pharaoh Sun
 Wild Tiki
 Freedom 7
 Burning Tiger
 Bao Bei Cash

Dragon Blast
 Shining Dragon
 Temple Cash

CACI (NASA Contractor)

May 2017 - December 2017

Software Engineer (Contract)

- Fixed issues and developed features for NASA's Trick Simulation Environment
- Integrated Trick engine simulations with the Unity 3D Game Engine to provide a visual representation of simulation objects
- Significantly refactored the Trick documentation to improve readability and user experience

Algebra Readiness Educators, LLC

June 2011 - Present

Wearer of Many Hats

- Designed and implemented the company website
 - Responsible for a 10 fold increase in total book sales
 - Now the primary venue through which purchase orders are submitted
- Designed book covers for 12+ mathematical workbooks
- Created business cards, booth displays, postcards, t-shirts, and other marketing materials

Education

B.S. Computer Science December 2016
Lamar University Beaumont, TX
Mirabeau Scholar 3.792 Major GPA